<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Scubed Software]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.scubedsoft.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.scubedsoft.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-17T15:22:37-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.scubedsoft.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Hubert Lee]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[June 2014 NYC Tech Breakfast]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.scubedsoft.com/blog/2014/06/17/june-2014-nyc-tech-breakfast/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-17T11:09:59-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.scubedsoft.com/blog/2014/06/17/june-2014-nyc-tech-breakfast</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
  <img src='images/posts/2014-06-17-secondmic.jpg' title='SecondMic presenting at NYC Tech Breakfast' />
</p>
<p>
  This morning, I attended my second
  <a href='http://www.meetup.com/NYC-TechBreakfast/'>NYC Tech Breakfast</a>.
  I like the format of this Meetup as they encourage startups to actually do a
  live demo of their product (and discourage &#8220;death by Powerpoint&#8221;), the
  MC is quite good, and there&#8217;s free food!
</p>
<p>
  As usual, there were five startups demoing their products to the audience.
</p>
<!-- more -->
<h3>
  <a href='http://www.basepair.io/'>Basepair</a>
</h3>
<p>
  First up was Basepair, demoed by Amit Sinha. Basepair is a SaaS startup
  providing DNA sequencing analysis to doctors, clinicians, and researchers.
  Users simply upload their DNA sequence data to the service and then select
  amongst a few predefined workflows to analyze their data. The results are then
  provided as a series of files accessible online.
</p>
<p>
  Basepair aims to replace the ad-hoc, developed-in-house workflows for
  analyzing DNA sequence data that many hospitals and reseach groups rely on
  now. These non-standard processes make it difficult for the doctors and
  researchers to perform analyses because the workflows are currently highly
  technical and require the assistance of a programmer or technician.
</p>
<h3>
  <a href='http://get.infomous.com/'>Infomous</a>
</h3>
<p>
  Next up, Paolo Gaudiano demoed Infomous. Infomous creates word clouds somewhat
  similar to
  <a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tag_cloud'>tag clouds</a>.
  The difference is that the words within these Infomous word clouds are
  semantically related to each other so that words within the same cloud have
  some sort of assocation and relevancy with each other. Users can click the
  words within the cloud to see a list of relevant webpages associated with that
  word. One interesting feature Paolo mentioned was that their algorithm does
  not rely on any natural language processing or semantic analysis to generate
  these word clouds, thereby enabling their technology to generate word clouds
  in any language.
</p>
<p>
  Infomous is currently focusing on providing these word clouds for news
  outlets. One cloud Paolo demoed was a retrospective of the big news stories
  from 2013. I found it to be a very creative way to visualize the events of
  the past year.
</p>
<h3>
  <a href='http://www.getyapper.com/'>Yapper</a>
</h3>
<p>
  Justin Lichtenstaedter and Rob Wyant, two fresh graduates from George
  Washington University, demoed Yapper next. Yapper provides users with
  hyper-local, ephemeral chat rooms to enable discussions that are relevant only
  to the current time and place. Their iOS-only app features support for public,
  private, and featured chat rooms, all of which expire after two hours.
  User-created chat rooms are limited to a five-block radius for participants,
  but the two also described a D.C.-wide chat room that they created for GWU
  students to coordinate activities.
</p>
<p>
  The two founders demoed a chat room they created for NYC Tech Breakfast and
  were able to get a few audience members to join and chat (surprisingly few
  members of the audience actually had iOS devices, so many were unable to
  download the app).
</p>
<h3>
  <a href='http://www.secondmic.com/'>SecondMic</a>
</h3>
<p>
  Fourth was Andre Pacheco who presented SecondMic. SecondMic is an iOS app that
  allows sports fans to commentate on games and broadcast live right from their
  iPhone or iPad. Other fans can then subscribe to the channels created by
  these amateur commentators and follow along with them in real time.
  With the 2014 World Cup happening right now, this app couldn&#8217;t have been more
  timely.
</p>
<p>
  Apparently, the &#8220;secret sauce&#8221; is in the technology that allows SecondMic to
  ensure that commentators and the viewers are watching the game in sync. Andre
  made a distinction between fans who watch games on broadcast TV over the air
  and those who watch games streamed online. Online streams tend to lag behind
  broadcasts over the air and it would ruin the viewing experience if streamers
  heard commentary that was even a few seconds ahead.
</p>
<p>
  Andre also discussed some of the legal challenges that SecondMic faces. The
  sports leagues own the rights to images, sounds, and descriptions of games, so
  it is actually illegal for commentators to give a straight play-by-play of
  games. Instead, they must provide some analysis or other commentary in their
  broadcasts.
</p>
<p>
  SecondMic was easily the most popular technology demoed at this Tech
  Breakfast and my personal favorite as well.
</p>
<h3>
  <a href='https://www.thejetway.com/'>Jetway</a>
</h3>
<p>
  Last but not least, Wen Wen Lam and Alexey Pakhomov introduced Jetway, a
  startup for providing corporate discount rates on flights and hotels to small
  businesses. Jetway provides a modern online flight booking experience to
  travel agents (some of whom still maintain a lot of their records on paper).
  When asked how they managed to get these rates, Wen Wen mentioned that they
  had to spend a lot of time in painstaking negotiations with their partners
  (that seemed to be all she felt comfortable sharing).
</p>
<h3>Final Thoughts</h3>
<p>
  I really enjoyed hearing about the startups that presented at this NYC Tech
  Breakfast. They all introduced innovative services that are already available.
  It&#8217;s a shame I won&#8217;t be around for the next one!
</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coworking Spaces in NYC]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.scubedsoft.com/blog/2014/05/22/coworking-spaces-in-nyc/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-22T10:04:32-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.scubedsoft.com/blog/2014/05/22/coworking-spaces-in-nyc</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
  The other day, I visited several co-working spaces in New York City based on
  <a href='http://thenextweb.com/insider/2011/08/17/the-5-coolest-coworking-spaces-in-new-york-city/'>this article</a>
  (which I now realize is from 2011). Here&#8217;s my take (ordered by my preference).
</p>
<!-- more -->
<ol>
  <li>
    <p>
      <a href='http://nwc.co/'>New Work City</a>
    </p>
    <section>
      <h4>Likes</h4>
      <ul>
        <li>
          Free equipment to borrow! Spare monitors + adapters and other
          electronic miscellany.
        </li>
        <li>A good-sized, well-stocked kitchen</li>
        <li>
          A couple &#8220;phone booth&#8221; rooms for phone calls. The rooms aren&#8217;t very
          soundproof though.
        </li>
        <li>
          Essentially no closing time. If you want to stay late, the staff can
          teach you how to lock up.
        </li>
      </ul>
      <br />
    </section>
    <section>
      <h4>Dislikes</h4>
      <ul>
        <li>
          Squeeky floors could be distracting. Can probably be mitigated with
          headphones
        </li>
      </ul>
      <br />
    </section>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>
      <a href='http://makeshiftsociety.com/'>Makeshift Society</a>
      (Bonus!)
    </p>
    <section>
      <h4>Likes</h4>
      <ul>
        <li>Huge windows with lots of natural lighting</li>
        <li>Basement level with kitchen</li>
        <li>Whiteboards have a wooden finish</li>
      </ul>
      <br />
    </section>
    <section>
      <h4>Dislikes</h4>
      <ul>
        <li>Located in Brooklyn (less convenient for me)</li>
        <li>Large, open space can be loud/echoey</li>
      </ul>
      <br />
    </section>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>
      <a href='http://fueled.com/coworking-space-nyc/'>Fueled Collective</a>
    </p>
    <p>
      I wasn&#8217;t able to get a tour per-se, but I did get to look around the
      space.
    </p>
    <section>
      <h4>Likes</h4>
      <ul>
        <li>Huge space with lovely decor</li>
        <li>24-hour access</li>
      </ul>
      <br />
    </section>
    <section>
      <h4>Dislikes</h4>
      <ul>
        <li>3-month minimum</li>
      </ul>
      <br />
    </section>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>
      <a href='https://generalassemb.ly/'>General Assembly</a>
    </p>
    <section>
      <h4>Likes</h4>
      <ul>
        <li>Wide open space and separate wings with cubicle like spaces</li>
        <li>Electronic signs indicate when conference rooms are booked</li>
      </ul>
      <br />
    </section>
    <section>
      <h4>Dislikes</h4>
      <ul>
        <li>No longer a coworking space as of January 2014.</li>
      </ul>
      <br />
    </section>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>
      <a href='http://www.wework.com/'>WeWork Labs</a>
    </p>
    <p>
      WeWork has many locations around New York City offering private offices,
      dedicated desks, and hot desks. I finally scheduled a visit to their Soho
      offices and have been back for meetings a few times since.
      <br />
      <del>
        They were short on staff when I visited, so were unable to give me a
        tour. I&#8217;ll update this post when I get a chance to visit the
        space.
      </del>
      <br />
    </p>
    <section>
      <h4>Likes</h4>
      <ul>
        <li>Large lounge area for hot desks</li>
        <li>Private office section includes small lounges to take a break</li>
      </ul>
      <br />
    </section>
    <section>
      <h4>Dislikes</h4>
      <ul>
        <li>Office spaces can be a little small</li>
      </ul>
      <br />
    </section>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>
      <a href='http://www.projectivenyc.com/'>Projective Space</a>
    </p>
    <p>
      <del>
        No one was home to say hello, so I didn&#8217;t get a chance to see the space.
        Perhaps another day.
      </del>
      <br />
    </p>
    <section>
      <h4>Likes</h4>
      <ul>
        <li>Wide open spaces</li>
      </ul>
      <br />
    </section>
    <section>
      <h4>Dislikes</h4>
      <ul>
        <li>Can be quite noisy</li>
      </ul>
      <br />
    </section>
  </li>
</ol>
<h3>Final Thoughts</h3>
<p>
  I really like the way these places keep the old interior of the buildings.
  Sometimes the floors are a little squeeky, but it gives each place a unique
  character that is just so hard to replicate.
</p>
<p>
  Many of these coworking spaces don&#8217;t seem to open on the
  weekends. Perhaps that&#8217;s just a hint to quit working and get out to have some
  fun!
</p>
<p>Update 6/17/2014: Added WeWork and Projective Space details</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scubed Software Is Visiting New York!]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.scubedsoft.com/blog/2014/05/18/visiting-nyc/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-18T10:20:12-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.scubedsoft.com/blog/2014/05/18/visiting-nyc</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
  From May 18 to July 14, I will be visiting New York City (and
  a few other locations)!
</p>
<p>
  During this period, I will be available for
  some part-time work. If you&#8217;re looking for some technical expertise,
  particularly in Ruby on Rails, reach out to me at
  <a href='mailto:hubert@scubedsoft.com'>hubert@scubedsoft.com</a>.
</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
